GAUTAM SAPRE

gautamsapre@gmail.com | +1 (617) 396 - 1452 | 1704 Yellowthroat Dr, Little Elm, TX 75068 | linkedin.com/in/gautam-sapre | gautamssapre.com

SUMMARY

Results-driven and passionate software developer experienced with Programming languages such as JAVA, Python (Django), C++, etc, and technologies such as Git, Unix, etc. Enthusiastic web developer with experience in database management. Manages a team of Industry Coordinators at the Association of Computing Machinery (HackUTD) and is an Operations Coordinator at the Artificial Intelligence Society.

EXPERIENCE

Industry Lead, ACM - HackUTD

Aug 2020 - Present

- Manage a team of HackUTD Industry Coordinators to host the biggest hackathon in North Texas.
- Set up meetings and keep up to date with the team's work to make sure conflicts are getting cleared

Industry Coordinator, ACM - HackUTD

Dec 2019 - Mar 2021

- In charge of finding sponsors for the largest hackathon in North Texas.
- Duties include maintaining relations with companies and accommodate their needs. And also figure out perks for each tier of the sponsorship packet.
- Contacted companies like Microsoft, Google, Walmart Tech, IBM, etc.

Tutor, Spider Smart

Jul 2019 - Present

- Responsible for making changes for the betterment of the business. Updated required logs and student
- documentation to keep records accurate and current.
- Created a model to track student progress, it figures out students' progress to date and recommends what needs to be done next.
- Taught SAT Math students, worked out problems, and explained theories as needed.

PROJECTS

Carpool

- Created an android application to let users match with people to carpool with who are traveling to and from the same location. Implemented a chat application that lets the users talk to people matched with.
- Utilized the Firebase database to store users' data. Technologies used Java (Android Studio), Google Autocomplete API and Firebase

Lossless Compression Algorithm

- Used MIPS Assembly language to compress and decompress text. Created a genuine encryption algorithm for data encryption.
- Currently working on generating a random compression algorithm every time the algorithm is used. Technologies used
 MIPS assembly language.

TravelSecure

- Utilized blockchain technologies to implement an airline insurance app that refunds money instantly through cryptocurrency when flights are canceled/delayed.
- Incorporated Metamask API and learned more about blockchain technologies. Technologies used Java, Blockchain, and Metamask API.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Courses: C/C++ in a Unix Environment, Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Data Structures and Algorithms, Discrete Mathematics I & II, Linear Algebra, Probability and Statistics in CS, Programming Languages
- Organizations: Association of Computing Machinery (HackUTD): Industry Lead, Artificial Intelligence Society: Operations Coordinator
- Awards: Academic Excellence Scholarship at the Honors Level Recipient

SKILLS

Languages: JAVA, C++, Python, Javascript, NodeJS, Django, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Markdown, Mips

Technologies: Git, Linux, Unix, Firebase

Tools: Github, Postman, Trello, Jira, Command Line, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Slack, Microsoft Teams Soft: Entrepreneurship, Project Management, Adaptability, Conflict resolution, Communication Skills, Mentorship

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science The University of Texas at Dallas High School Diploma, Coppell High School Aug 2018 - Present